<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>net.zdechov.app.C-evo</id>

  <name>C-evo: New Horizons</name>
  <summary>Turn-based empire building game</summary>
  <developer id="net.zdechov.chronos">
    <name>Chronos</name>
  </developer>

  <url type="homepage">https://app.zdechov.net/c-evo/</url>
  <url type="contact">https://app.zdechov.net/c-evo#Support</url>

  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <project_license>CC0-1.0</project_license>

  <description>
    <p>With a time scope of several thousand years, it covers aspects of exploration and expansion, industry and agriculture, warfare and diplomacy, science and administration.
    C-evo follows the spirit of popular turn-based strategy games from the mid 90s, but with more emphasis on powerful AI and careful design of the rules, resulting in a true challenge.</p>
    <p>It is a turn-based strategy game inspired by Civilization 2 game where you can build your own empire.</p>
    <p>New Horizons edition is a continuation of the last released original C-evo version with many quality improvements:</p>
    <ul>
      <li>Full Linux platform support</li>
      <li>Zoomable map by mouse wheel with three tile sizes</li>
      <li>User defined key mapping</li>
      <li>Many sample maps included</li>
      <li>Multiple localizations included</li>
      <li>High DPI and scaling support</li>
      <li>Multi monitor support</li>
      <li>In-game background music</li>
      <li>And much more</li>
    </ul>
  </description>

  <launchable type="desktop-id">net.zdechov.app.C-evo.desktop</launchable>

  <branding>
    <color type="primary" scheme_preference="light">#cdab8f</color>
    <color type="primary" scheme_preference="dark">#63452c</color>
  </branding>

  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <caption>Game interface and world map</caption>
      <image>https://svn.zdechov.net/c-evo/tags/1.3.8/Screenshots/Game.jpg</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <caption>Main menu</caption>
      <image>https://svn.zdechov.net/c-evo/tags/1.3.8/Screenshots/Main%20menu.jpg</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <caption>Start of a new game</caption>
      <image>https://svn.zdechov.net/c-evo/tags/1.3.8/Screenshots/New%20game.jpg</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <caption>Multiple opened windows</caption>
      <image>https://svn.zdechov.net/c-evo/tags/1.3.8/Screenshots/Windows.jpg</image>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>

  <releases>
    <release version="1.3.8" date="2025-08-01" type="stable">
      <url type="details">https://svn.zdechov.net/c-evo/tags/1.3.8/Release%20notes.txt</url>
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>Added: Ability to play music in background in start screen and in-game. Used uos as audio library.</li>
          <li>Added: Allow to switch music on/off from game window main menu.</li>
          <li>Added: Music volume option in game settings form.</li>
          <li>Added: Package Music files with option to not install them.</li>
          <li>Added: Allow to move with up, down, page up, page down, home and end keys in selection dialog.</li>
          <li>Added: Open product selection dialog with P key in city dialog.</li>
          <li>Added: Close city dialog with return key.</li>
          <li>Modified: Improved forms painting if resized to bigger dimensions.</li>
          <li>Modified: Auto select newly saved game as last game in previous games list.</li>
          <li>Modified: Evaluate Escape key in Settings dialog.</li>
          <li>Fixed: World size was always set to minimum on start.</li>
          <li>Fixed: Wrong AI brain selection if only one AI available.</li>
          <li>Fixed: Make selected book or map visible in the list on application start.</li>
          <li>Fixed: Repaint start window after language change in settings window.</li>
          <li>Fixed: Fixed unit move style hostile calculation in StdAI. Engineers don't take hostile damage on hostile terrain.</li>
          <li>Fixed: Do not process keyboard input during unit attack on Linux.</li>
          <li>Fixed: Limit world size loaded from registry.</li>
          <li>Fixed: Images in Help window were not found if located under share directory.</li>
          <li>Fixed: Black strip on the bottom of Draft dialog.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.3.7" date="2025-02-26" type="stable">
      <url type="details">https://svn.zdechov.net/c-evo/tags/1.3.7/Release%20notes.txt</url>
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>Added: AppImage packaging files.</li>
          <li>Added: AI upscaled C-evo icon to 1024x1024 resolution.</li>
          <li>Modified: Improved brains libraries enumeration.</li>
          <li>Modified: Detect data files usr/share/c-evo directory on Linux as relative directory to usr/bin directory.</li>
          <li>Modified: Updated french translation.</li>
          <li>Modified: Used larger icon for the executable.</li>
          <li>Fixed: Recalculate unit list size if the main window was resized.</li>
          <li>Fixed: Do not scroll map if mouse is outside of window region.</li>
          <li>Fixed: Restored background transparency in C-evo icons.</li>
          <li>Fixed: Invalidated rectangle in AI tournament was not properly scaled.</li>
          <li>Fixed: Log and AI turnament windows were not shown correctly.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.3.6" date="2024-09-16" type="stable">
      <url type="details">https://svn.zdechov.net/c-evo/tags/1.3.6/Release%20notes.txt</url>
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>Added: Allow to scroll map with Ctrl+arrows/num keys.</li>
          <li>Added: New editor menu action to create filled map from selected tile.</li>
          <li>Added: Allow to rename city with mouse right click on city caption in City screen.</li>
          <li>Added: Spiral of death map.</li>
          <li>Modified: Show windows by default on primary screen if multiple monitors present.</li>
          <li>Modified: Do not use Screen Width and Height values for Offscreen bitmap size initialization to improve multi monitor support.</li>
          <li>Modified: Map scrolling with mouse on window borders instead of screen borders to support mouse scrolling in windowed mode and on multiple monitors.</li>
          <li>Modified: Precalculate scaling coefficients also for from native values conversions for faster speed.</li>
          <li>Modified: Scroll just by single row with mouse wheel in tile units list.</li>
          <li>Fixed: Do not process keyboard input during unit move on Linux.</li>
          <li>Fixed: Resize main window controls on game start if map size changed.</li>
          <li>Fixed: Allow full screen switching in editor and movie mode.</li>
          <li>Fixed: Do not overflow city name text in City screen.</li>
          <li>Fixed: Repaint main screen after city and unit rename.</li>
          <li>Fixed: Rows scrolling of high number of units in single map tile.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
  </releases>

  <categories>
    <category>Game</category>
    <category>StrategyGame</category>
  </categories>

  <content_rating type="oars-1.1">
    <content_attribute id="violence-fantasy">moderate</content_attribute>
  </content_rating>
</component>
