<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="desktop-application">
  <content_rating type="oars-1.0" />
  <id>com.mitchellh.ghostty</id>
  <metadata_license>MIT</metadata_license>
  <project_license>MIT</project_license>
  <name>Ghostty</name>
  <icon type="remote">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ghostty-org/ghostty/refs/heads/main/images/icons/icon_256.png</icon>
  <summary>Fast, native, feature-rich terminal emulator pushing modern features</summary>
  <description>
    <p>
      Ghostty is a terminal emulator that differentiates itself by being fast,
      feature-rich, and native. While there are many excellent terminal
      emulators available, they all force you to choose between speed,
      features, or native UIs.  Ghostty provides all three.
    </p>

    <p>
      In all categories, I am not trying to claim that Ghostty is the best
      (i.e. the fastest, most feature-rich, or most native). But Ghostty is
      competitive in all three categories and Ghostty doesn't make you choose
      between them.
    </p>

    <p>
      Ghostty also intends to push the boundaries of what is possible with a
      terminal emulator by exposing modern, opt-in features that enable CLI
      tool developers to build more feature rich, interactive applications.
    </p>

    <p>
      While aiming for this ambitious goal, our first step is to make Ghostty
      one of the best fully standards compliant terminal emulator, remaining
      compatible with all existing shells and software while supporting all of
      the latest terminal innovations in the ecosystem. You can use Ghostty as
      a drop-in replacement for your existing terminal emulator.
    </p>
  </description>

  <launchable type="desktop-id">com.mitchellh.ghostty.desktop</launchable>

  <url type="homepage">https://ghostty.org/</url>
  <url type="help">https://ghostty.org/docs/about</url>
  <url type="bugtracker">https://github.com/ghostty-org/ghostty/issues</url>

<!-- tbd
  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <caption>Use background image attachments</caption>
      <image>https://ghostty.org/tbd-screenshot.png</image>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>
-->

  <developer id="com.mitchellh">
    <name>Mitchell Hashimoto</name>
  </developer>

  <releases>
    <release version="v1.0.1+1" date="2025-01-09">
      <description>
        <p>
          Initial AppImage build.
        </p>
      </description>
    </release>
  </releases>
</component>
